Tianyin Zhang

(408)609-4697 | tianyinzhang1999@gmail.com | San Jose, CA 95148

SUMMARY

A creative and forward-thinking Computer Science major who enjoys web development as well as learning new technology. Experienced software developer, team contributor, and analytical problem-solver with strong learning capability and communication skills. Specifically aims to solve ambiguous problems with practical solutions.

SKILLS

- Programming Language: JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Tools: Figma, Photoshop, MongoDB, Firebase, ExpressJS, ReactJS, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, Jira, Git/Github, CommandLine.
- Agile Methodology, Scrum Framework
- Time and Tasks Management, Organization and Coordination, Collaborative working
- Hobbies: Personal Electric Vehicle, Photography, Videography.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer, MERN Mobile Web App, January 2023-May 2023

- Develop a mobile-focused web app using ReactJS, ExpressJS, NodeJS, MongoDB.
- Follow the Agile methodology and Scrum Framework.
- Assists other developers with coding, troubleshooting, and debugging.
- Produce high-quality code artifacts that conformed to standards and best practices.

Full Stack Web Developer, JavaScript Web App, September 2022-December 2022

- Developed a multi-page web app that uses JavaScript, React.JS, Firebase (database, Auth, Hosting), HTML, and CSS.
- Managed both back-end and front-end aspects of the development process.
- Code review, version-control duties, debugging, and refactoring code base.
- Working under agile methodology and Scrum Framework, serving the team as the Scrum Master.

Founder, PEV NYC, October 2021-Current

- Founded, managed, and develop a local non-profit PEV hobbyist group with healthy growth.
- Engage sponsors and coordinate events for relative businesses in the industry.
- Promoting green energy, no-impact transportation methods.

Founder, Discord Gaming Community, March 2018-December 2019

- Started one of the biggest student-focused online gaming communities.
- Attracted 30,000 total members within the first 1.5 years.
- Managed a team of moderators to maintain a healthy community environment.
- Hosted various online events such as tournaments, talent shows, etc.

EDUCATION

BA in Computer Science, New York University | New York, NY | Expected in May 2023

- Computer Science with a focus on JavaScript and related tech stack.
- Courses taken: Data Structures, Web Dev & Programming, Basic Algorithm, Computer System Organization, Operating Systems, Applied Internet Technology, Remote Collaborating, Agile Software Development & DevOps, Data Management and Analysis.